hey everyone welcome back to our Channel
I am back with another interesting topic
in the Tosca automation playlist
in this session we are going to look at
how we can backup and restore
repositories on Tosca Commander
now Tosca Commander allows us to backup
and restore uh two types of items one is
the entire projects it could be either a
single user project or a multi-user
project
it also allows us to uh backup and
restore component folders which are
nothing but uh smaller projects inside
your big project so backing up a single
user project is pretty simple
so for example this particular single
user project can be backed up by just uh
exporting the subset
and then whenever you want to restore
this project then you can just import it
again so exporting a subset is pretty
easy click on export subset and then
here I can store
some name like the same name
so it will store this as practice dot
TSU okay
so this way you can easily take a backup
of your current single user project and
then whenever you need it you just
import the subset again maybe in a
different project okay so just go ahead
and import the practice dot TSU okay
so I'll click on open and then it is
going to ask you to merge all the
different objects because this is the
same project right so
don't do it on the same project uh
probably do it on a different project
where you want to recover this
now coming to
the multi-user projects it's a little
different okay than single user projects
so for multi-user projects uh the backup
includes all the workspace objects the
project settings uh properties and also
if you have got any version data
the main uh prerequisites before you uh
take a backup of your multi-user project
is you should make sure that you have
got enough disk space because the backup
file could be about 20 percent of the
size of your backed up Repository
and to restore the database repositories
you need create and drop rights
so let's go ahead and open a multi-user
project now uh like this multi demo
and then the process involves you to
open the workspace as an admin user so
only an administrator can take a backup
of a multi-user project
so we are going to sign in using the
admin credentials
and after this uh you have to go to
Project
and then info here there is an option to
backup the currently used common
Repository
okay so click on that and then it will
ask you to exclude object versioning
history from the backup you can click
yes or you can click no okay
and then it will ask you for a folder
where you want to store this particular
backed up a repository okay so let's go
ahead and create a backup folder here
and then I'm going to select that and
click on OK
now depending on your repository size
this could take uh minutes or hours
right uh since my repository doesn't
contain uh much objects so it was done
in a quick instance but uh it could be
different uh based on your repository
size
so that's how you can backup your
multi-user project it will be stored in
the file extension of dot TDP okay so
that's that's the file extension and
then in order to restore a particular
backup okay so we don't need to go into
any project so we are going to close
this
and Crescent is actually recommends that
whenever you restore a backed up
repository
it should always be in a newly created
repository okay
because if you restore your backup in a
existing repository try sentence Tosca
is going to overwrite all the existing
data
so you should not be doing it in
existing repository you should always do
it in a new Repository
so here uh we need to go into project
again info and then we need to go into
the restore option which is now
available because we have got a backup
so click on that restore and it will say
that when restoring any existing data in
the affected repository will be
discarded
uh you will not be able to undo or roll
back this transaction okay so make sure
you are aware of this before you restore
your particular project into this
repository okay
so here it will ask you for a restore DB
repository selected file so we can go to
that particular location where we store
this dosca workspaces
and then uh in the backup folder okay so
this is the file multi demo dump and it
is dot tgp right
so uh after this after so after that you
click on open
okay and then it will ask you for the
type of repository okay so it could be a
new repository an actual database like
Oracle Ms SQL or db2 or it could be a
sqlite okay and then
um the connection string okay so if you
are using Oracle or a SQL Server uh
schema is optional and then you click on
test connection and then click on OK OK
so uh this is going to overwrite all the
all the data in the particular
repository right so I am not going to do
that
but this is always helpful uh when you
have got regular backups of your
repository or your projects then in in
very rare scenarios where you lose any
particular data due to any particular
problem in your database or in your
complete infrastructure then you can
always use this backup to restore your
repository or project uh in a different
repository right
that's all for this particular video if
you have any questions then please leave
it in the comments if you like this
video then please subscribe to our
Channel
thanks for watching and I will see you
in the next video